People tend to be way too scared of
leaving their jobs.
>> This is Jay Jo. He went from a software
engineer at Robin Hood to a successful
founder raising $35 million and he
shared everything he learned along the
way. You were playing the game doing the
minimum but still getting promoted.
How'd you do that? I think at Robin Hood
it was probably easier than it would
have been at like a Meta or like one of
these other bigger companies. You worked
at Robin Hood during the whole GameStop
saga. That day there were so many people
that just reached out to me like, "Yo,
man, what the hell is going on?"
>> Eventually, Jay left Robin Hood to start
his own company after getting jaded
about career growth. You raised $35
million. You must have learned something
in that [music] process.
>> That was one of the worst times in the
history of crypto to be raising money.
What's the clear case of here's the
value that crypto provides the world?
Here's the full episode.
[music]
you started your own crypto company
where the market cap of the coin is
worth over $10 billion. I kind of want
to go over your career story, hear each
of the legs at, you know, Facebook,
Robin Hood, what made you want to leave?
So, maybe we can start with the Facebook
part of the saga. So, you know, how did
you first get into big tech? What's the
story behind that?
>> I feel like life is not linear for
anyone. I mean ups and downs, but I
think when there are ups that happen,
they tend to be kind of like step
function improvements uh versus just
being like linear growth. Um and in the
case of myself when I was in college, I
I really wanted to get like one of these
brand name internships. I don't have a
good reason for why. I think it was just
kind of like mimemetic in a way. Like I
just wanted what everyone else wanted.
Um and at that time it felt like there
were two internships that were like the
cream of the crop which were like the
Facebook and Google internships. I'm
like I really want to get this. Um, and
when I was a sophomore, I was basically
just grinding all the time. Like I was
fortunate where I was in a spot where I
was able to get interviews with a lot of
these companies. Um, and I'm like,
"Okay, I'm just going to like go into
hermit mode and try to get um try to get
one of these internships." And at that
time, I was not necessarily like very
good at these leak code type of
problems. Um, so what ended up happening
was, uh, there's one of our friends,
Vic, he organized this event called Leak
Code and Chill. And it's basically where
a bunch of like honestly like a bunch of
CS guys got together uh one evening. It
was like Friday night or something and
we're just solving lead code problems
together and sounds hella nerdy and it I
mean honestly was um but there was one
problem that we went over there which is
called number of islands which is a
pretty kind of classic problem uh which
is like you either do a breath for
search or depth for search to be able to
identify the number of like uh connected
islands that are there and that ended up
being the exact question that I got
during my second like during the on-site
of my Facebook internship interview and
yeah it was just like bizarre like if I
had not gone to that event I would not
have got my Facebook internship and
without that Facebook internship, I
don't think any of the things that
happened afterwards in my career would
have really materialized. So yeah, it
was just like a totally random lucky
coincidence.
>> You said Google and Facebook were the
cream of the What about those other ones
like uh if I recall correctly, Palunteer
was pretty good back then. There's also,
you know, the finance ones too.
>> That's true. That's true. So I think
what you value is a function of what
other people around you value and are
talking about. Um I think my social
circle wasn't really talking about those
other companies as much like uh if for
example you went to difference college
then maybe like these high frequency
trading shops would be viewed as more
prestigious. I think amongst my social
circle at UCLA it was very much at that
time like Google and Facebook and then I
noticed after I became older in that
circle um there were other companies
that started to be viewed as more
prestigious like uh the palunteers to
like a lot of these preipo companies as
well. you uh got the internship at
Facebook you which is the dream at the
time and how was the experience when you
actually were doing the internship was
not that fun to be completely honest
from from my perspective and I think
it's just because it felt very um
impersonal in a way it was better than
in some ways than like the previous
internship that I'd had the summer
before uh but I did want to try
exploring being in a smaller environment
and I think that led me the next summer
to work at Pinterest and that was like
as a Kleiner Perkins fellow. So I'm
like, "Oh, I'm going to get like ideally
the full kind of like startup exposure."
Pinterest was definitely a much better I
would say experience. I think part of it
was just that it was based in San
Francisco. So it was uh much better
culture just like being in the city at
the time. Um but I think also because it
was a smaller company, there was a much
closerk knit intern class and that
allowed me to have much more meaningful
friendships. Like uh from my Facebook
internship class, I'm not really in
touch with too many people. I think from
my Pinterest internship class, I'm still
in touch with like four or five guys.
I'm like I'm super close to them. So, it
was just very different in terms of the
kind of atmosphere that it uh they
created.
>> You had the Pinterest internship and
then after school you decided to go with
Robin Hood, right?
>> Exactly. So, at that time, I was about
to graduate. I mean, I was uh this was
like September, October, so like my
senior year. Um and at that time, I had
a couple of options. I could either go
back to Pinterest and I was like not too
enthusiastic about that. Like I had a
great internship experience but a lot of
my friends weren't going back over
there. So I was like it might not make
as much sense to go back over there if
the biggest reason was like more this uh
social reason. The second thing was
getting a master's degree and UCLA has
this like fifth year or I guess you can
automatically get admitted to the
master's program. So I was like this is
something that I'm like seriously
considering. Um, and then I just decided
to interview for a few different places
as well. Um, and what I was basically
looking for is a small environment where
I felt like I could be surrounded by
people that would be doing pretty
significant things in the future. And
Robin Hood was one of the places that I
talked to. So I went to this thing
called Greylock Tech Fair. Um, they
basically rent out what's called now um,
Oracle Arena, the the big the big
stadium in SF,
>> right?
>> Um, and they basically invite a bunch of
interns to come over there, but it's
like invite only. So most companies
don't have very long lines to like go
and talk uh to these companies at the
booths. Um in the case of Robin Hood
back in 2017, that was like the longest
line that they had. Like there were like
a couple hundred people that are waiting
in line to talk to those folks from
Robin Hood. And I was like, "Okay, this
is actually pretty interesting to look
at, like to learn more about cuz I
didn't know too much about trading back
then. I wasn't really managing any
brokerage accounts." Um and that led to
me like talking to the folks over there
and I just thought it was a really
really strong team. I ended up going
over there and in hindsight I feel like
that was absolutely the right decision.
Like getting a master's degree, I don't
think that would have mattered at all
for my career. Um going to Pinterest, I
think that would have not been as
positive as going to Robin Hood. Um in
Robin Hood's case, I think there were
some things that ended up being just
phenomenal. Uh first of all, I think the
caliber of person that was joining at
that time was really really high. So
even for my new grad class, around a
third of the people in that new grad
class, they went on to raise money. So
like they they basically started
ventureback companies. And I think
that's a much higher percentage than you
see at most at most companies. But I
think there was a lot of really strong
people over there. And on top of that,
when you're at a company that's scaling
so quickly, when you're running into
like all these scaling problems, like
you just end up getting exposed to a lot
more stuff, so you learn a lot more. Um,
and I think you also have much faster
career growth as a result of that. Uh,
definitely more so than you would at
like a smaller startup where things
don't really change year to year where
like you're just trying to find PMF, it
doesn't work. You do the same thing
again, doesn't work. their time. Um, so
yeah, I'm definitely very grateful for
that experience at Robin Hood.
>> What series was Robin Hood at the time?
>> Uh, when I signed the offer, it was
series C. When I joined, it was series
D. But when I signed the offer, it was
around 100 people at the the company.
And so it was basically one building,
like two buildings across the street
from one another. And one of them was
actually a house. So they had like
bedrooms in that house that people were
working from. So they had like standing
desks where engineers were actually
working from. Yeah, it was a much much
smaller environment than Pinterest was.
>> I think the most common take for you
know the high EV job or a new grad is go
to big tech, get the stamp and you go
into that big environment. I feel like
you have a completely contradictory
opinion to that. So what is the what is
the rationale for smaller in this case?
>> To be fair, I think I did have the stamp
from the internship. So I think it was
>> you didn't have that.
>> Yeah, it might have been a different
decision if I didn't have that. But I do
think that you basically have to pick
what you're optimizing for in your
career. If you're optimizing for I mean
TC, let's say, uh I mean you're not
going to be hitting the ceiling by going
to a big tech company. Like the only way
you can get like the max upside is by
going to a very early stage company and
kind of hitting it out of the park. Um
if you're trying to optimize for
learning, you're going to definitely
have much better learning opportunities
at a smaller company that's like
actually growing very quickly. Um, so I
think you kind of need to figure out
what that thing you're optimizing for
is. In my case, it became clear like I
didn't care as much about money as I did
about growth. Um, both from the learning
standpoint and also from the career
growth standpoint. And that's why I
decided to go to Robin Hood. Um, I don't
think my career growth was actually as
fast as I had anticipated it to be over
there. Um, it kind of felt just like a
normal uh normal company career growth,
but I I do think it ended up being much
better from the uh kind of learning
standpoint. Yeah, that is a common thing
that I hear is like you go to the small
company for learning. I do kind of feel
like the small company it's like the
high variance path. Like I could see a
case where you learn much more but I
could see also a case where like the
company you know stops growing and it's
like you know you're really not learning
as much.
>> Yeah.
>> But I could also see cases of big tech
where the team is like getting reorged
like crazy.
>> Yeah. I think I mean across the board it
definitely depends on how lucky you get
with whatever position you end up in,
>> right?
>> Probably the biggest thing you can
control is the kind of person you're
going to be working with cuz you don't
know what the career prospects are going
to be for any startup. Like maybe you're
working on something that sounds
brilliant at the time but then it just
isn't able to get as much traction as
you need to raise next round of money
for example. Um so I do think optimizing
for like surrounding yourself with
really smart people gives you the best
chance of learning a lot more than you
otherwise would and that could be like a
pretty good heristic people use when
they're deciding where to go.
Definitely. And so you said you you
started working at Robin Hood. You were
expecting a lot of growth and it sounds
like it was not what you expected. I
went in thinking that I'd be able to
have pretty fast career growth. And for
context over there, um I think I
honestly just joined a bit too late.
Like by the time I started it was series
D. the people that had joined around
series A, series B time frame, I think
they did end up having the kind of
growth that I was hoping for, which is
like moving up the ladder really
quickly, becoming engineering managers
or like even higher than that in like a
2 three year time horizon. Um, in my
case, I joined and I think at that point
it was already starting to manifest into
more of like a big company type of
progression. So, at my three-month mark,
they were having performance reviews,
but I couldn't participate in them
because I joined like one or two weeks
too late. So, I had to participate in
the one six months after that. So, at my
9month mark, I like went through the
entire perview process. And I've been
like busting my ass for the 9 months
before then. There were several days
where I was working till like 2 a.m.
just actually working. Um, and our on
call rotation back then was also
horrendous because there's this thing
called overnight batch where after
market closes each day, you need to do a
bunch of stuff before market opens the
next day. In our case, there was a lot
of manual intervention that was
required. Hopefully now it's fixed. So,
if there's any Robin Node engineers
listening, hopefully it's better for you
now. Um, but back in our day, it was
just horrendous. So, I mean, honestly,
there were several times that it went to
like 4:00 or 5:00 a.m. and it was like
actually dangerously close to causing
like a business issue for Al because if
you're not done with the batch process
by the time market opens the next day,
there's like Yeah, definitely a lot of
downside there.
>> What is the batch pro like what do you
need to actually do?
>> So, there's things like uh trade
settlement that needs to happen. And so
you need to be working with a lot of
different counterparties externally just
to make sure that like everything like
all the different parties have accounted
for everything uh to be the same across
all their systems. It's basically just a
bunch of batch jobs need to run one
after the other. But if any of them
fail, you need to figure out why it
failed and then fix it if there's like
some kind of like issue from like the
actual codebase side. Get it out and
then move on to the rest of the process.
So imagine that there's like some
deployment that happen and there's like
hundreds of different bad jobs. So there
could be like a three four different
deployments that happened that day.
There might be two issues that got uh
that got deployed and then these batch
jobs failed at let's say 11 p.m. at
night. You need to page the person who
wrote that. They need to fix it. They
need to like deploy the new code. Then
you have to go through that process
again and kind of just like go through
with it. So I I do think that Robin
Hood's code base has not been
architected in the most kind of stable
way possible and they did end up having
a bunch of tech debt as a result of
that. But yeah, I guess the core point
was that I felt like I'd been working
really hard and then I got like the
performance rating which was the
performance rating itself was like five
out of five. So I'm like okay that's
pretty atypical for people to get so I'm
happy about that. But then there was
like nothing else tied to that. There
was like no promotion, no compensation
change tied to that. And I was just like
why why did I do this? Cuz when you're
like 22 there's a lot of things you
could be investing your time into. And I
felt like if I had just been not
investing so much time into work, I
would have had a lot more happiness. Um,
I don't know if that actually would have
materialized in the same way if I hadn't
been, but they it did feel like the
amount of time I was putting in was not
commensurate with the reward I was
getting. And I was just like, okay, so
then I should just kind of be a little
more checked out and just like trying to
go through the motions of like playing
the game in a way. And that just made me
super jaded about like this kind of big
tech kind of environment cuz it does
feel like a lot of people are just going
through the motions playing the game and
I felt like there could be something
bigger to work towards than that
>> and that happened 9 months in but you
were there for 3 and 1/2 years.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
So my situation was a little complex of
a couple of reasons. There was like a
death in the family which made it harder
for me to leave. Um, on top of that,
they also gave us options that were
expensive to exercise. So, it would have
cost me $400,000 to exercise my options,
which I didn't have 400k lying around. I
would have like needed to take out a
loan or something. So, my game plan at
the time was to just stick around until
there was some way to get out of that,
which would have either been um the way
that they set it up was if you stayed
long enough, then you wouldn't need to
exercise the options before leaving.
They give you 7 years afterwards. That
was like one strategy. The other
strategy was to just wait for the IPO to
happen.
>> And the IPO ended up happening in July
of 2021. And that's when I kind of had
like my handcuffs removed in a way. I
could like do whatever I wanted to at
that time. Um, that's when I started
like just going a lot more deep, a lot
deeper into crypto and kind of exploring
like what we could be building over
there.
>> When you look back, you mentioned like,
you know, compensation
starting at a pre-IPO startup compared
to like as if you had worked in big
tech. Um, did it did it net out to be
higher pay?
>> Yeah, I mean it's like an order of
magnitude higher than it would have been
at like uh spending three and a half
years at like a Google or Facebook type
of company,
>> right?
>> I mean, yeah. So, I think financially
that was like a fantastic decision in
hindsight, but at the time I kind of
felt like I was locked in without really
having too much flexibility. So, I think
that also detracted from my happiness.
>> And I think we definitely got lucky over
there as well. Like most of my friends
that joined preo companies, some of them
ended up IPOing. And so they were like
pretty happy about that. Um but a lot of
them just still haven't IPOed. So
they're kind of um they felt like
they've invested all this time and then
their stock options didn't really end up
being worth anything. And I think we got
pretty lucky too cuz I graduated in
2018. There are a lot of tech IPOs that
happened in 2021. So like my graduating
class, your graduating class, we were
pretty fortunate with that timing. I
think after that the IPO market cooled
down and there's been less and less
IPOs. like someone that graduated in
like 2020 for example, I don't think
they would have had that same kind of
liquidation opportunity
>> when it comes to your career growth. I
mean, sounds like you were a little bit
checked out. Was there were you going
for promotions or getting them or you
were kind of coasting?
>> I was I mean I I still got promoted the
second performance cycle and then
afterwards before leaving I was
technically up for promotion. Um, so at
that point I was playing the game still,
but I wasn't really investing too much
mental energy into it or like too much
time into it. One way of thinking about
it is I was putting in the bare minimum
to make sure that I was like close to
average. Um, and yeah, then I was
spending my time elsewhere.
>> When you think about I guess is you were
playing the game doing the minimum but
still getting promoted like what how'd
you do that? Yeah, I think at Rob Node
it was probably easier than it would
have been at like a Meta or like one of
these other bigger companies because I
joined and the company just grew 10x
after that. So I like became a domain
expert pretty like just just because of
that in a way cuz like we were hiring a
lot of people were starting to build a
lot of new services. So just by the fact
that I existed and I was in the seat at
that time I was the only person that
knew how to do like 10 different things.
And once you're given that much kind of
responsibility, then it's pretty easy to
become someone that's viewed as like an
expert and can be relied upon to like
solve different problems. So I think I
was a competent engineer that just knew
a lot of stuff and that made it very
easy for me to get promoted the second
time. And I I think that's what was
happening as well for my uh second
promotion if that had ended up
happening. Like I was already an
engineering lead because I was like
doing stuff for like a few different
systems. So I think I was just kind of
given that responsibility.
>> I see. So it sounds like just by default
in a high growth environment if you are
competent you become loadbearing.
>> Yeah, I I definitely think that if it's
like a high growth environment where
both the team grows and like the work to
do also grows then 100%.
>> And because of that there were also a
lot of opportunities I got that I
probably wouldn't have gotten at a
bigger company. Like I mentored three
different people. Like my first person
that I mentored was like a year and a
half in roughly um to the start of my
job over there and I feel like a lot of
bigger companies that might be less
common like you don't get your first
mentee or like your first intern until
you're like much more senior.
>> Right. Right. So it sounds like I mean
you know a lot of career trajectories
and things are opportunity luck you know
things outside of our control but it
sounds like two things that were you
know a throughine here was that you you
sought out talented people or like you
went where talented people were and you
went towards like a high growth
environment. Yeah.
>> And those things just kind of
>> you know working together led to
promotions even though you weren't
really even trying for them.
And also your conversation was uh also
good as well. Um I understand that you
worked at Robin Hood during the whole
GameStop saga.
>> What was that like from the inside?
>> Yeah, I mean so for anyone that doesn't
have context into it like
>> uh when the GameStop saga happened,
there were like 12 stocks. It was like
GameStop, AMC, and like 10 other ones
that I don't remember right now. Um all
of them were just like straight ripping
because this is like when COVID was
happening so people had gotten their
like steamy checks as well if I recall
and yeah I mean people were just like
gambling a lot in a way. Um and these
stocks started going up in value so like
hedge funds and a lot of institutional
traders were like okay we think that
this based on a fundamental analysis
like this valuation no longer makes
sense so we're going to short it because
we think it'll eventually return to
normal. Uh the issue with shorting a
stock though is that you have to borrow
the stock then you sell it and then when
you want to close that position you have
to buy that stock back and then return
it. So when you buy that stock back it
leads to the price of that stock going
up. So when the price is going up and
people have to start closing their short
positions that leads to more buy
pressure from those shorts being closed
which causes a short squeeze. So all
these stocks had short squeezes
happening on them. Um, and in a way it
was like the little guy was beating the
big guy because these institutions were
leading. Robin Hood was the place where
everyone was going to trade. And then I
think it was like January 28th of 2021.
Uh, Robin Hood just turned off buys on
all these meme stocks. And it was insane
because I found out about it when I woke
up and I was like, damn, this is crazy.
And then that day there were so many
people that just reached out to me like,
yo, man, what the hell is going on? Cuz
a lot of them, I think, were actually
financially invested in this as well.
And when Robin Nonoff is the price of
GameStop started to go down, so they're
like understandably like quite pissed
about that. Um, and yeah, I mean it just
makes you feel super powerless when
you're an insider at a situation like
that. And one thing that I realized is
just how that that really reinforced me
just how archaic our current financial
system is. In the case of Robin Hood,
that happened because there's this
concept of T plus2 settlement that back
then it used to take two days for trades
to settle. And during this time, Robin
Hood needed to have collateral for the
positions that people were opening. So,
they needed to actually give
counterparties like billions of dollars
on January 28th if they wanted to let
people keep trading these assets. Um,
and like normal people don't know about
any of that stuff and it only exists
because these are like the ramifications
of the traditional financial system that
was built like whatever the current
version I think was built like 40 years
ago for example. It kind of made very
clear to me that we will need much
better financial rails in the future and
that was one of the things that led to
the inspiration for say
>> oh that's that's interesting. So, cuz I
remember that moment when they turned
off the buys. And I think the the public
narrative was that they were doing it on
purpose to manipulate the price, but
sounds like you're saying it was just
logistical. They just couldn't support
the trades.
>> Yeah. So, Robin Hood did not turn off
the buys because they were trying to
like [__] with the price or whatever.
Um, they did turn off the buys because
they needed to put up more collateral.
And I think they miscommunicated this
potentially on purpose. Like they were
saying that like we didn't turn off the
buys for XYZ. Um even though that was
actually the case and I think that's
because they were actively fundraising
because they needed to raise billions of
dollars at that same time.
>> So it was like this really difficult
thing that Vlad and Beij were trying to
do at the time. I don't know what the
right way to do that would have been cuz
it was basically they were fighting for
their company's existence at the time in
a way. Um especially when regulators
didn't really like them to begin with.
So things could have gone very very
wrong over there. So I think all things
considered they did navigate that in an
okay way but I think they could have
communicated to the public um a lot
better.
>> Okay. So it sounds like you were getting
promoted but you were you know
disengaged and trying to leave. What's
the story behind you eventually leaving
and wanting to start a startup?
>> Yeah. So I mean from a I mean growing up
in Silicon Valley the people that are
the most respected there are not like
sports stars or like Hollywood stars. It
is basically entrepreneurs. Like growing
up everyone would talk about like Steve
Jobs for example instead of like Madonna
or whatever. And yeah I mean I think
everyone like if you're growing up in
Silicon Valley like consider starting
something at some point. In my case, I
did that Kleiner Perkins fellowship
where it seemed a lot more accessible in
a way like there were a lot of folks
there that had started their own
companies or a lot of folks that are
considering starting it. So I think
being surrounded by that kind of group
when I was uh 21 um I was like okay it's
doable to start something. And then uh
in 2019 me and my co-founder my current
co-founder um we decided to actually
start trying to build things together.
So this is like after uh promotion
didn't work out. I'm like, what should I
do with my life? Um, so nights and
weekends were basically trying to get
this like AWS cost management startup
off the ground. And it's such a boring
boring space to be in cuz literally your
job is to help people cut down on cloud
costs. And what that means is if there's
a super high growth company, they're not
going to be interested in working with
you because they're growing so quickly
that it'll be easy for them to raise
more money in the future. So the only
kind of companies that you can really
work with are ones that are like kind of
atrophying in a way. And because we're
small, it's not even going to be like
the big companies that are atrophying
that would work with us. It' be like
these series A, series B companies that
have kind of stalled out in growth and
need to start cutting their cost. That's
a horrible customer to have. Like that
that's not someone that you want to
really build your business off of. Um so
yeah, I mean we didn't find too much
traction with that. Honestly, thank God
for that cuz I don't think I would have
liked spending several years of my life
working on that. Um that's like the
first thing that we did back in 2019.
Then 2021 we decided to like start
spending a lot more time in crypto.
There are different ideas that we kind
of looked into but ultimately what we
decided we wanted to do was building
something like Robin Hood except
building it in a decentralized way. And
the thinking is that if it was built in
a decentralized way you'd be able to
solve all the issues that were happening
with the Robin Hood saga like the
graintop saga that we're talking about.
Um and that led to us initially building
a central limit order book based
exchange onchain. Um and I'll I guess
I'll avoid going too deep in the details
over there but essentially we're
initially trying to build uh an exchange
which is an application and we realized
it's actually better to build the
infrastructure for that application
which led to say and that's around when
I quit my job and we just went kind of
all in on it.
>> What did you need to see before you went
all in? So, in our case, we had
basically a team of people that was like
willing to work part-time with us. I
think that helped. Um, we had a good
relationship, me and my co-founder, and
I think that we started seeing some
initial kind of excitement around what
we're building. And that's when I kind
of pulled the trigger. Um, I think my my
bar for pulling the trigger was lower
than it would be for a lot of other
people cuz like the IPO had just
happened financially. There wasn't much
downside for me to do that because I was
hitting the end of my four-year grant
anyway. So I was like this is this is
the time and didn't hindsight that was
like a fantastic time to kind of pull
the trigger.
>> Imagine that Robin Hood had a like
compensation wise let's say had a
middling performance or like it was just
uh you know normal as if you had like
worked at Google or like a big tech
company. Mhm.
>> Do you think you still would have uh
left to start your own company with the
same conviction or do you think that you
money is a big part of that?
>> I think it would have been even easier
to make that decision honestly because
the 6 months of equity that I left on
the table was still a dollar value that
was pretty high to me. Um if it had been
like a normal kind of uh compensation
that I'd be leaving on the table, I
don't think it would have been a hard
decision at all. Uh, in general, I think
people tend to be way too scared of
leaving their jobs. Most of the time, if
you're like competent, things will work
out anyway. Like, I don't know too many
people that are like that are good at
their jobs at company A that are not
able to find any work again after that.
Actually, I don't know anyone like that.
Um, typically if someone's good at
company A, they have no trouble finding
a job somewhere else. Um, so yeah, I
think people tend to overindex on how
much risk they're taking on when they
leave to start something.
>> I see. I see. Okay. Okay. So, you're
saying it's not that big of a deal and
you can just go back or you can find
another opportunity if it if it fails.
>> Exactly. I mean, if you're a software
engineer working in tech, I think it's
there it's such little downside in a
way. There's just the opportunity cost
for the most part. If you spend like a
year trying to get something off the
ground, it doesn't work out. Not only
are you like I would actually say you're
more valuable to a startup or like to
any kind of company, if you've been
through the reps of actually trying to
start something um than than you would
expect. Like I think a lot of people
worry that like oh yeah if I'm not
working on anything like if I'm not
working as a software engineer for a
year then it'll be hard for me to get a
job. But if you're going through the
reps of like actually trying to build a
product you end up learning a lot more
that makes you more valuable to any kind
of business.
>> Like what are those things that you
learn? Like for example, getting uh
product validation, like coming up with
a product idea, being able to see if
people actually care about it, then
working through the entire life cycle of
like designing the product, actually
building it from the engineering side,
going to market with it, like the
marketing side around that, the business
development side around that. So there's
just so many things that is a normal
engineer, you don't have to do it all.
And in this case you end up just
learning all of that which when you go
as an engineer to any company um if
you're able to play the roles of like
being a marketer being a product manager
like being a business development guy as
well um I think you're able to do a much
better job of building the product and
you're also able to play a much bigger
role in like the eventual go to market
of that that product as well. What what
about in the the bare case I guess let's
say you you quit your job you are
working on something that where you
don't establish PMF and you don't have a
I guess a marketable you know milestone
in that thing that you did but you did
get the skills but you know who's going
to say who's going to give them
credibility if you know you just
wandered and like explored ideas so I
don't think big companies will give you
that much credibility I think a lot of
early stage startups would like if you
go and interview at a startup that's
like a seed or preede startup. Um they
would be very happy to work with an
engineer that's been a previous founder
much more so than they would a normal
engineer just because that founder that
that engineer can be much more impactful
in like the 0ero to1 process that you're
uh that you're getting started with.
>> Right. Okay. So it's kind of I mean if
you do choose to make that career
decision it doesn't necessarily pigeon
hole you but your career starts to bias
a little more towards smaller companies.
I think smaller companies is where
you're going to excel more. Um, but I
also think there's this other side of it
where people that try to start a
company, they're already biased towards
smaller companies. So, they're much more
likely to only interview for these
smaller companies after their startup
doesn't work out. And that's going to be
where there's like more interesting
problems for them to work on anyway. So,
you probably do see more examples of
that of like people leaving to start a
company, failing, and then going to
another small company. But, I don't
think that's just because big companies
say no. I think that's also because
that's the environment that those
founders want to find themselves in.
Yeah. No, there's definitely some um
confounding factors for sure. And I've
seen examples of people big tech, left
big tech, started something, failed,
came right back to big tech. So, you
know,
>> that's true.
>> You can you can definitely do that as
well. Um I want to talk about
fundraising because I mean your startup
thankfully was successful and you raised
a lot of money. I don't know the total.
Maybe you could.
>> Uh we raised 35 mil in total.
>> Okay. Um, we raised a 5 mil seed round
and then afterwards we had like
strategic rounds that end up being uh
for 30 mil.
>> Okay. So, you raised $35 million. Um,
you must have learned something in that
process. I'm curious, what was that
like?
>> Yeah. So, our seed round, we started
raising it right after there was this
blockchain called Terra, which is one of
the biggest blockchains out there. It
collapsed and then we started raising
our seed round 3 weeks after that. That
was one of the worst times in the
history of crypto to be raising money.
Um, so we learned a lot about I mean
rejection obviously because most most
investors said no to us. I mean we
obviously learned like what the end to
end life cycle for like fundraising
looks like cuz we hadn't raised money
before then. Um so like the intro calls
then eventually meeting the partners and
like kind of talking through the team,
the product, the vision, all that all
that kind of jazz. Um it's actually not
that not that scary in a way. And there
is a bunch of group things that happens
like initially everyone's kind of like
skeptical and then once one fund becomes
excited about something it makes it much
easier to convince other funds to get on
board with it. And there's a lot of
investors that are just like kind of on
the sidelines trying to maintain as much
optionality as they can. So they like
give excuses a lot of the time like oh
yeah we're like still doing diligence.
We'll get back to you in like a week or
something just to see like how the deal
plays out. So there is definitely that
aspect of like trying to get people more
excited about the investment. I see. And
so, so it sounds like the most impactful
thing here is you get a good lead and
then all the sheep will come.
>> Yeah. If you get a tier one lead
investor, everything else is super easy
after that.
>> So then how did you get your your lead
investor and like what's that process
look like if you're just a you know
engineer with a product?
>> Yeah. So in our case, we just got an
intro to a bunch of different like I
mean basically every investor that's
like a top tier investor um in crypto.
One of the funds we talked to was
Multicoin. Uh, Multicoin was the biggest
investor in Salana and they've made
billions of dollars from that
investment. So, I would say that's like
they're regarded as like one of the top
five to 10 investors in crypto. Um, and
we had really good conversations with
them and they ultimately decided to uh
invest in us. And after that investment,
I think everything just became much much
easier cuz initially when you're getting
started with something, if you don't
have a track record, everyone's kind of
skeptical of you. But once you get that
stamp, it becomes much easier to open a
lot of doors. Whether it's for business
development opportunities, whether it's
for future fundraising, whether it's for
like anything required for the actual
launch as well, like it just becomes
significantly easier. Um, the other
thing that I'll say is that for crypto,
it's very different than traditional uh
kind of venture. Um, I think in
traditional venture, it's probably even
harder than it is in crypto. Um, because
in crypto, there's like a very different
type of um process. There's like
typically most projects they have like a
seed round, a series A and then
afterwards there's some kind of token
launch event that happens and then they
don't typically raise like institutional
or like venture capital rounds too much
after that. Whereas in like AI companies
or like most web two companies there's
like several rounds of fundraising that
need to happen and there's like a lot of
like um revenue and like financials that
people look at in in crypto. there's a
lot of a lot of like softer metrics
people look at but there's not really
the same concept of like revenue if
you're like helping build a blockchain.
Um and as a result of that like web two
companies like okay this is your ARR and
then that's like a very fundamental
metric like how quickly you're growing
around that. Um in the case of crypto
it's much more like how much excitement
is there around this project how many
teams are actually building with this.
So it seems reminiscent of like 1995 to
um in like internet investing where
there are a lot of like alternate
metrics people came up with like number
of eyeballs that like are looking at a
website for example um stuff like that.
So I I think it is much more of like a
subjective space to be investing in if
you're like an investor in crypto.
>> Let's say I'm a skeptical you know
software engineer and I looking at
crypto I think there's a lot of grift
there. what's the the bold case or
what's the clear case of here's the
value that crypto provides the world
>> yeah so I guess I mean two separate kind
of streams of thought over there the
first is that any industry that is an
early stage industry I think it tends to
have a ton of grift and a ton of things
that don't make sense um when web 2 when
like the internet was getting started
for example arguably the biggest use
case for it was porn right like that
that was one of the biggest things that
was taking off in web 2 back in like the
mid90s
And I would make the argument that the
internet has just completely changed
society. So I think it does take time
and I think there does tend to be a lot
of grift in any kind of new industry
that's getting started. I think even
with AI we're probably seeing semblances
of that where there's like a lot of
people that are raising money that
aren't really building anything super
meaningful um and that are probably like
misusing a lot of the funds that they're
getting. In crypto's case I think yeah
there's been a ton of events like that.
Um and I think that we're starting to
move like those events are becoming less
and less typical I think through a
couple of different things. Um the first
I think is there starting to be more and
more regulatory clarity. So once a
government gets involved sets clearer
guidelines around like what is
acceptable, what's not acceptable, I
think that grift naturally goes away. Um
and then there's also like the kind of
social policing that happens as well.
Like if you're seeing patterns where if
people do XYZ that results in bad things
happening um other people tend to be
less supportive of like investing in
founders that they think might do those
kinds of things. So it's becoming much
less common to see that kind of um
negative stuff happening I would say. Uh
in terms of where I see crypto going. So
my view on this is that crypto will be
playing a very big role in changing the
financial system in the future. And
right now there's two things that crypto
has been really really good at. It's
been really good at payments and it's
been really good at trading. And the
reason for that is when you have this
kind of distributed ledger, it adds in a
ton of cost cuz you're basically doing
the same thing many many times across a
bunch of different machines. Um, but the
benefit of that is verifiability. So
you're able to verify that you can trust
whatever this computation is because
you're like doing it yourself as well.
So the only use case that really really
makes sense over there is finance. Like
when there's actual money at stake, I
think that's going to be the biggest use
case where crypto can be really really
impactful. So right now I think it's
already playing a big role in terms of
like international remittances from the
stable coin side. Um, and I think in the
future, like when you start seeing more
and more stable coin adoption, that'll
lead to more financial rails being built
up around those stable coins. So, I
think in the future, like we're actually
going to have some version of just
completely decentralized Wall Street
getting built as well. That'll be
globally accessible that anyone's able
to trade on and basically make use of.
Um, another thing would be if you're in
a country that doesn't have a stable
currency, what do you actually hold your
money in? like unless you're investing
it into some kind of like stock market,
um you don't want to be holding a
currency that's like inflating, let's
say 30% in the course of like a couple
of days. So in that case, you'd actually
want to hold on to US dollars. But if
your country doesn't want you to get
easy access to US dollars, like what do
you do? Well, crypto is becoming one of
the clearly used solutions over there
where people just buy USDC or USDT and
they hold on to it and that's what they
transact in. So I'd say that's another
use case where crypto has been picking
up. um in Southeast Asia, Latin America,
it's being used a lot more for just
actual payments as well. I think that
it's just starting to become more and
more widely adopted over there. And
yeah, I mean I I definitely think in the
long term um the verifiability that
crypto offers is going to be really
really useful for allowing computation
to happen between people that don't
trust each other. Um which will be like
a lot of financial use cases for people
basically around the world. Coming to
the end here, when you look back on your
career, like which time do you feel like
you you had the most growth and and why?
>> Uh 2022 was the year that I had the most
growth undoubtedly.
>> And that was when you started the
company.
>> Yeah. When we that was like the Yeah.
When we started today. When you're at a
job, I think there's a lot of rails
there to help support you. When you
start a company yourself, like you're
all by yourself and you need to figure
everything out by yourself. Um, and
yeah, as a result of that, I think I
learned a lot. Um, but I think basically
every single year since then, I've
probably learned more than I did during
my like any of the jobs that I work for
other people.
>> I see. And these things that you're
learning are more of like the uh
non-engineering things. Like, okay. It's
like, you know, how do you start a
business? How do you fund raise? Like
>> Exactly. I think the engineering side of
things is generally pretty easy. Um,
definitely. I mean once you're like
going up the ladder at like a meta or
something you're solving really really
difficult problems but I don't think
most businesses need like they have
those kinds of problems and they don't
need support to solve those problems
like most businesses are solving pretty
mundane kind of problems. Um so from the
aspect of like building a product that
people use I don't think you typically
end up facing those kind of scaling
problems. Um, so if you're a competent,
let's say, uh, I I don't I forget the
leveling that Meta uses now, but like
Robin is like L3 is like a new grad, L4
is the level above it. If you're a
competent L4, then I think you can do
perfectly fine as a founder in um, any
kind of uh, from any kind of engineering
side.
>> So let's say I wanted to start my own
company. I'm a new grad. Would you
recommend stay until you hit that
minimum bar of technical competency
>> or just go for it? If you know what you
want to build, I think you should just
go for it. I think you'll be able to
either build that technical competency
or more likely hire for that technical
competency because if you have a good
idea, you have like and if you have a
good idea, it'll be pretty easy for you
to raise money. And if you raise money,
then it's going to be pretty
straightforward for you to grow a team
uh from there as well. And I mean, you
know, when we look back, I mean,
obviously hindsight's 2020, but your
startup has been successful in how has
the the team grown over the last few
years. And I'm curious like we can think
about that compared to like maybe big
tech levels and stuff and we can see
what those promos kind of look like.
>> Yeah. So, when we got started, it was
around I mean there were like five to
seven of us. This is in 2022. Um now
across like there's multiple entities
but if we combine all the entities it's
around 60 people working uh full-time on
say so we've been pretty lean in terms
of our growth relative to what I've seen
at places like Robinet for example um
and I think that was absolutely the
right decision like if you grow slowly
it allows you to maintain the culture
and it also prevents all the scaling
issues you see with like bureaucracy and
people kind of being clueless on what to
do. Um so that allows you to move more
quickly as well. I think the last thing
that I want to ask you is, you know, if
you were to go back to yourself right
when you had graduated from UCLA and
give yourself some advice knowing
everything you know now, what would you
say?
>> Yeah, I mean the main thing that comes
to mind right now is to not be so
scared. There's I I think I'm naturally
more of a risk averse person and as a
result of that I've been more hesitant
to basically take these big leaps of
faith. There's other people I know where
it's like very very easy for them to do
that for them to do that. And I do think
optimally like there is some kind of
middle ground where you think through
any decision you make but then
afterwards you pull the trigger quickly.
Um and I think that I shouldn't have
been scared at all about uh leaving my
job at Robin Hood even potentially
earlier on.
>> I see. So in a perfect world actually
you would have left earlier. In a
perfect world, I would have left
earlier, but then I don't know if things
would have played out the same way
because I might not have started a
crypto company in that case. And I think
that if it had been like like that AWS
cost management company, um I don't
think it would have been the same uh
kind of outcome.
>> Makes sense.
>> Cool. Well, thank you for your time,
Jay. Um you know, at the end of the
interview, is there anything you want to
plug?
>> Uh if you guys want to learn more about
today, you could just follow the same
network Twitter. S E I N E T W O R K.
Thanks.
>> Cool. All right. Thanks, Jay.
>> Thanks for listening to the podcast. I
don't sell anything or do sponsorships,
but if you want to help out with the
podcast, you can support by engaging
with the content on YouTube or on
Spotify. If you want to drop a review,
that'll be super helpful. And if there's
any guests that you want to bring on to,
please let me know. I feel like sourcing
very senior IC's, there's no wellstudied
list out there on Google that I can just
search this up. So, if there's someone
in your org or at your company who you
really look up to and you want to hear
their career story, let me know and I'll
reach out to